So you may have noticed something.
When we move our player character towards the right, they're moving and facing in the correct direction.
However, if we move our player character towards the left, they're moving towards the left, although
they're not facing the left in this lecture, we're going to fix that.
The first thing we're going to do is open up our player blueprint.
And if we create a new variable and just call this move right question mark and we're basically going
to use this variable to help tell the game if we should move towards the right and face the right or
if we should move towards the left and face the left, we can delete this print shrink as we now know
where it does.
And what we're going to do is we want to check the value of this action.
Value If this value is ever greater than zero, that basically means my player character must be pressing
the one.
And so we want them to face the right.
So if we just drag up here and look for Branch.
And correct from triggered into here.
And we just want to drag in this move, right.
And just set it and make sure it's checked.
Because if this value is greater than zero, that must mean my player character is moving towards the
right.
If this is false, then we won't do another branch.
And we want to check to see if this action value is less than zero.
If that is true, that means we want our player character to move towards the left.
So if we just drag in this move right, set it and just make sure it's unchecked, then connect it into
here and here and off of this false.
If you just connect this into the add movement input.
So what we've done is if our player character is ever moving towards the right, we've told the game
that this variable should be true.
However, if our player character is moving towards the left, then we've told this variable to be untrue.
The next thing I need you to do is look for this event, take note, and the way it works is every single
frame is going to run this node and on event ticket we're going to basically make sure that the player
character is facing the correct direction.
So over event Tick, we first want to drag in our character event and over here we'll look for velocity.
And we're going to get the velocity of our character.
We just want to right click on this value and click split structure pin.
We're only going to be concerned with the velocity of our character in x axis because as I mentioned
earlier in our two D game, our character is only going to be moving in the x axis and we're going to
do is we won't take a drag of here for compare look.
Now we're going to compare the velocity of our cat in the x axis with the values here in our characters.
Velocity in the x axis is ever greater than zero.
That means our player character should be facing towards the right.
So in order to make that happen, what we can do is just right click and forget control.
So get the controller that we're controlling the player character as and what we want to do is just
drag up here for is valid.
This will just make sure that we have a valid reference to our controller.
And if that is valid, then we're going to set the rotation of our player character to be facing towards
the right.
We can do that by dragging off this node and looking for a set control rotation.
Then under this new rotation value, we can strike up here and we'll make rotator.
And we can write the values that we want our character to have and the X, Y, and Z.
If I head over to the viewport and just select my Sprite, currently we can see my sprite rotation in
the x, Y, and Z is zero and my player character is facing the right.
So here in Minecraft, I'm just going to leave this value at 000.
If my player characters velocity in the x axis is ever less than zero, that means my player character
is moving towards the left.
We want our player character to be facing the left.
Some copy all these nodes press control C and then control V.
And from this node the left hand to here.
If I go back to my viewport and just like my Sprite in the Z.
If I make this value 180, my sprite will flip and they'll be facing towards the left.
I'm just going to put this back at zero.
And head over to my bank graph.
So when my characters velocity in the x axis is less than zero, I will make it so my character is facing
towards the left.
So here under Z we want to put a value of 180.
And if I play a character's velocity in the x axis is equal to zero.
Then what we're going to do is drag in this write variable, which will be determined by here.
And just track up here and look for Branch.
If the mood right variable is true and we'll make it so I'll play a character.
It's facing towards the right.
And if our right variable is false, we'll make it so our player character is facing towards the left.
And we'll just go from here to here and just go compile and save.
So I just close this and go play.
If I move towards the right, my captain, me to the right and equal to the left.
Whoops.
So that's not working.
If we head back to our player character.
We just want to set our spring goal and currently its rotation is set to relative.
We need to change it so that it's set to the world and go compile save.
Both this and now, if I could play.
When I pressed the right mouse button.
Sorry.
When I press the right on my capital mutual's the right.
If I press the left key on my character.
Move towards the left.
Now, normally in 2D platformer games, our character starts facing the right by default.
So under my play, BP.
Just make sure they'll move right variable is are checked so our character will start the game facing
towards the right.
So if I go play, my character starts facing towards the right and I can move around and jump.
The next thing I want to do is use the paper Z animation system to make it so a character will play
some different animations when they're jumping and moving.